import { Exercise } from ".";

export const FRUITS_AND_VEG: Exercise[] = [
  {
    "question": "яблоко",
    "answer": "jabłoko",
    "extra": "🍎"
  },
  {
    "question": "банан",
    "answer": "banan",
    "extra": "🍌"
  },
  {
    "question": "виноград",
    "answer": "winogrod",
    "extra": "🍇"
  },
  {
    "question": "апельсин",
    "answer": "apiel´sin",
    "extra": "🍊"
  },
  {
    "question": "лимон",
    "answer": "limon",
    "extra": "🍋"
  },
  {
    "question": "арбуз",
    "answer": "arbuz",
    "extra": "🍉"
  },
  {
    "question": "клубника",
    "answer": "klubnika",
    "extra": "🍓"
  },
  {
    "question": "вишня",
    "answer": "wisznia",
    "extra": "🍒"
  },
  {
    "question": "персик",
    "answer": "pirsik",
    "extra": "🍑"
  },
  {
    "question": "ананас",
    "answer": "ananas",
    "extra": "🍍"
  },
  {
    "question": "кокос",
    "answer": "kokos",
    "extra": "🥥"
  },
  {
    "question": "киви",
    "answer": "kiwi",
    "extra": "🥝"
  },
  {
    "question": "помидор",
    "answer": "pomidor",
    "extra": "🍅"
  },
  {
    "question": "огурец",
    "answer": "oguriec",
    "extra": "🥒"
  },
  {
    "question": "морковь",
    "answer": "morkow´",
    "extra": "🥕"
  },
  {
    "question": "баклажан",
    "answer": "bakłażan",
    "extra": "🍆"
  },
  {
    "question": "перец",
    "answer": "pieriec",
    "extra": "🌶️"
  },
  {
    "question": "картофель",
    "answer": "kartofiel´",
    "extra": "🥔"
  },
  {
    "question": "капуста",
    "answer": "kapusta",
    "extra": "🥬"
  },
  {
    "question": "лук",
    "answer": "łuk",
    "extra": "🧅"
  },
  {
    "question": "чеснок",
    "answer": "cziesnok",
    "extra": "🧄"
  },
  {
    "question": "гриб",
    "answer": "grib",
    "extra": "🍄"
  },
  {
    "question": "кукуруза",
    "answer": "kukuruza",
    "extra": "🌽"
  },
  {
    "question": "слива",
    "answer": "sliwa",
    "extra": "🍑"
  },
  {
    "question": "груша",
    "answer": "grusza",
    "extra": "🍐"
  },
  {
    "question": "дыня",
    "answer": "dynja",
    "extra": "🍈"
  },
  {
    "question": "манго",
    "answer": "mango",
    "extra": "🥭"
  },
  {
    "question": "лим",
    "answer": "lim",
    "extra": "🟢"
  },
  {
    "question": "ежевика",
    "answer": "jeżewika",
    "extra": "🍇"
  },
  {
    "question": "кабачок",
    "answer": "kabaszok",
    "extra": "🥒"
  }
];
